<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Famous Historical Statisticians on Stat 150 at Cal Poly</title>
    <link>/categories/famous-historical-statisticians/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Famous Historical Statisticians on Stat 150 at Cal Poly</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/famous-historical-statisticians/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How a Guiness Beer Brewer Created T-Tests</title>
      <link>/2019/11/how-a-guiness-beer-brewer-created-t-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/how-a-guiness-beer-brewer-created-t-tests/</guid>
      <description>“The rule of law can be wiped out in one misguided, however, well intentioned, generation”-William Gosset
 Although William Sealy Gosset is one of the least known contributors to modern statistics, his work is still widely referenced today. He was born in Canterbury, England on June 13, 1876 to Agnes Sealy Vidal and Colonel Frederic Gosset. Gosset attended Winchester College before studying chemistry and mathematics at Oxford.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Famous Historical Statistician: Florence Nightengale</title>
      <link>/2019/10/famous-historical-statistician-florence-nightengale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/famous-historical-statistician-florence-nightengale/</guid>
      <description>“To understand God’s thoughts, we must understand statistics for these are the measure of His purpose” -Florence Nightengale
For our famous statistician we researched Florence Nightengale. Florence was born in Florence, Italy in 1820. She used statistics to improve her practice of nursing and in doing so became one of the founders of modern nursing. She kept records of every one of all her patients was known for using effective graphical representations of her data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>