<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Famous Statisticians on Stat 150 at Cal Poly</title>
    <link>/categories/famous-statisticians/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Famous Statisticians on Stat 150 at Cal Poly</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/famous-statisticians/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Karl Pearson</title>
      <link>/2019/11/karl-pearson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/karl-pearson/</guid>
      <description>“I look upon statistics as the handmaid of medicine, but on that very account I hold that it befits medicine to treat her handmaid with proper respect, and not to prostitute her services for controversial or personal purposes.”- Karl Pearson
(https://www.britannica.com/biography/Karl-Pearson)(https://todayinsci.com/P/Pearson_Karl/PearsonKarl-Quotations.htm)
Karl Pearson served as a leading founder in the modern field of statistics. Born in 1857 in London, England, Pearson spent many of his early years following the religious beliefs of his Quaker ancestry and it wasn’t until his mid-twenties that he decided to lean away from that, opting instead to explore his academic interests while slowly becoming more of an agnostic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Allan Rossman</title>
      <link>/2019/11/allan-rossman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/allan-rossman/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Teaser text or links here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Statistics students at Cal Poly have long known that they were the cool kids on campus, but it’s nice to see a major newspaper broadcast this news to the rest of the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://statweb.calpoly.edu/rossman&#34;&gt;This is a link to his personal website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daniela Witten</title>
      <link>/2019/11/daniela-witten/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/daniela-witten/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Banning p-values as a way to reduce irreproducibility in science is like banning strep tests as a way to reduce the prevalence of strep. As in, it does not work”
- Daniela Witten&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Tukey</title>
      <link>/2019/11/john-tukey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/john-tukey/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The best thing about being a statistician is that you get to play in everyone’s backyard.”
- John Tukey&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Florence Nightingale</title>
      <link>/2019/10/florence-nightingale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/florence-nightingale/</guid>
      <description>“The world is put back by the death of everyone who has to sacrifice the development of his or her peculiar gifts to conventionality.”- Florence Nightingale
Florence Nightingale is a prominent figure in the nursing world, well known for her work during the Crimean war and for founding the first professional nursing school in the world. Nightingale worked with the British government to improve sanitation in field hospitals, while also improving nutrition and acquiring more medical supplies for the soldiers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nate Silver</title>
      <link>/2019/10/nate-silver/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/nate-silver/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The irony is that by being less focused on your results, you may achieve better ones.”
― Nate Silver&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ronald Fisher</title>
      <link>/2019/10/ronald-fisher/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/ronald-fisher/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The best time to plan an experiment is after you’ve done it.”
- Ronald Fisher&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gertrude Cox</title>
      <link>/2019/10/gertrude-cox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/gertrude-cox/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The field of statistics is certainly wide open to women. If you are willing to take the mathematics and science courses and then work very hard … there are all sorts of opportunities to go as far as you wish. - Gertrude Cox&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gertrude Cox</title>
      <link>/2019/10/gertrude-cox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/gertrude-cox/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Polynomials are notoriously untrustworthy when extrapolated.”
- Gertrude Cox&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hadley Wickham</title>
      <link>/2019/10/hadley-wickham/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/hadley-wickham/</guid>
      <description>Hadley Wickham was born in the city of Hamilton, New Zealand, in 1979. He started his statistics career at a young age when, at 15, he developed Microsoft Access Databases that the company still uses today. Statistics runs in the Wickham family; his father has a PhD in statistics and his sister Charlotte is an assistant professor of statistics at Oregon State University. Wickham switched gears and received a bachelor’s degree in biology from the University of Auckland, NZ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hadley Wickham</title>
      <link>/2019/10/hadley-wickham/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/hadley-wickham/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the attributes that has made me successful is that I am exquisitely sensitive to
frustration. - Hadley Wickham&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>