<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ethics Topic on Stat 150 at Cal Poly</title>
    <link>/categories/ethics-topic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ethics Topic on Stat 150 at Cal Poly</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/ethics-topic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Research Ethics and The Belmont Report</title>
      <link>/2019/10/human-research-ethics-and-the-belmont-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/human-research-ethics-and-the-belmont-report/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;The National Research Act for the Protection of Human Subjects of Biomedical and Behavioral Research was signed into law in 1974, and without this act today, many more individuals may have passed away due to violation of basic human ethics in research experiments. The focus of this act revolved rules regarding human experiments, such as having respect for persons, beneficence, and justice Research experiments have previously targeted powerless individuals, so this act marked huge progress in scientific research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hhs.gov/ohrp/regulations-and-policy/belmont-report/read-the-belmont-report/index.html&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://www.hhs.gov/ohrp/regulations-and-policy/belmont-report/read-the-belmont-report/index.html&lt;/a&gt;)
(&lt;a href=&#34;https://research.calpoly.edu/HS-guidelines&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://research.calpoly.edu/HS-guidelines&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Know Your Rights as a Test Subject</title>
      <link>/2019/10/know-your-rights-as-a-test-subject/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/know-your-rights-as-a-test-subject/</guid>
      <description>While the advent of scientific experiments has provided countless contributions to mankind, it is important that ethics get highly considered before the conduction of such experiments. After numerous atrocities were committed during WWII including the use of human subjects, the Nuremberg code was drafted to impose guidelines upon physicians and scientists as to how to treat their subjects. The three main sections of this code include: the distinction between research and practice, a discussion of the three basic principles of ethics, and the applications of these principles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsible Statistic Education and Common Misinterpretations</title>
      <link>/2019/10/responsible-statistic-education-and-common-misinterpretations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/responsible-statistic-education-and-common-misinterpretations/</guid>
      <description>An understanding of statistics is necessary to be able to correctly interpret the data we see and understand it’s validity. However, there are many common misunderstandings surrounding statistics and probability. Without an understanding of the validity of findings, people, even those who have been taught introductory statistics, can be led to false conclusions with real world consequences.
Responsible Statistic Education and Common Misinterpretations
Statistics used to be a small area of study, reserved for researchers to analyze their results.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>