<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stats in the News on Stat 150 at Cal Poly</title>
    <link>/categories/stats-in-the-news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stats in the News on Stat 150 at Cal Poly</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/stats-in-the-news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats In The News</title>
      <link>/2019/10/stats-in-the-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/stats-in-the-news/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;There seems to be a perception among Americans that vaping is less harmful than tobacco products, and the article “What percentage of Americans Vape”by Zach Hrynowski from Gallup, wanted to better understand the scale of vape use in America. Click here to learn about what this poll concluded about adults use of vape in America.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vape Statistics are Getting to be a Little Spooky</title>
      <link>/2019/10/vape-statistics-are-getting-to-be-a-little-spooky/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/vape-statistics-are-getting-to-be-a-little-spooky/</guid>
      <description>“Fear strikes the hearts of teens as data begins to depict a trend of vape products leading to illness”
https://www.esquire.com/lifestyle/health/a29343883/vaping-illness-epidemic-cdc-director-interview/
It appears that a long-existing act that has more recently gained a surge in popularity has finally been connected to some terrifying consequences. The article above focuses on an interview between the media and Dr. Robert Redfield, the director of the CDC, who appears to be prominently concerned about the alarming number of cases involving repeated usage of vape products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Approval of Trump&#39;s Impeachment really Improving?</title>
      <link>/2019/10/is-approval-of-trumps-impeachment-really-improving/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/is-approval-of-trumps-impeachment-really-improving/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Have you read headlines about impeachment, or Donald Trump’s approval rating going down? This article captures the statistics behind presidential popularity and all the biases that often surround it. For instance, differential nonresponse bias may be causing an appearance of increased support for impeachment, when in reality public perception has not changed. The survey method used to draw opinion results are flawed in that the responses vary by the means of who is responding and who is not - an error pollsters still have to work on in order to “cancel out” the nonresponse bias.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>