<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Section 01 on Stat 150 at Cal Poly</title>
    <link>/tags/section-01/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Section 01 on Stat 150 at Cal Poly</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/section-01/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gertrude Cox</title>
      <link>/2019/10/gertrude-cox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/gertrude-cox/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The field of statistics is certainly wide open to women. If you are willing to take the mathematics and science courses and then work very hard … there are all sorts of opportunities to go as far as you wish. - Gertrude Cox&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hadley Wickham</title>
      <link>/2019/10/hadley-wickham/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/hadley-wickham/</guid>
      <description>Hadley Wickham was born in the city of Hamilton, New Zealand, in 1979. He started his statistics career at a young age when, at 15, he developed Microsoft Access Databases that the company still uses today. Statistics runs in the Wickham family; his father has a PhD in statistics and his sister Charlotte is an assistant professor of statistics at Oregon State University. Wickham switched gears and received a bachelor’s degree in biology from the University of Auckland, NZ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minard’s Graphic of Napoleon in Russia</title>
      <link>/2019/10/minards-graphic-of-napoleon-in-russia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/minards-graphic-of-napoleon-in-russia/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Are you guys tired of the same boring graphs to represent data? Well, Charles Joseph Minard in 1869 certainly was. To represent Napoleon sending 400,000 troops out to attack Russia in response to Czar Alexander of Russia refusing to adhere to Napoleon’s embargo on the UK, Minard used an elegant graph depicting not only the number of troops, but also temperature and the path of the march over a map of Europe. Rather than simply showing data, Minard had a focus on story-telling which would inspire statisticians for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Null Results</title>
      <link>/2019/10/null-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/null-results/</guid>
      <description>In today’s scientific studies, researchers are becoming increasingly selective in what results they choose to write about and even more selective in what they publish. In his article “Why null results rarely see the light of day”, Jeffery Mervis details the prominent issue of bias toward writing and publishing strong results over null results in modern research while acknowledging the potential dangers of overemphasizing the publication of null results.In recent times, it has been overtly evident that social science experiments have been heavily in favor of writing and publication of strong results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polish Village Hasn’t Seen A Boy Born In Nearly 10 Years</title>
      <link>/2019/10/polish-village-hasnt-seen-a-boy-born-in-nearly-10-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/polish-village-hasnt-seen-a-boy-born-in-nearly-10-years/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://theconversation.com/polish-village-hasnt-seen-a-boy-born-in-nearly-10-years-heres-how-that-computes-122176&#34;&gt;Link to Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>