<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Analysis on Stat 150 at Cal Poly</title>
    <link>/categories/data-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Analysis on Stat 150 at Cal Poly</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/data-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Old psych experiments aren&#39;t just cruel, but also invalid.</title>
      <link>/2019/10/old-psych-experiments-arent-just-cruel-but-also-invalid./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/old-psych-experiments-arent-just-cruel-but-also-invalid./</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;The Stanford Prison Experiment was a study conducted by Philip Zimbardo, a Stanford psychologist who ran the study at Stanford University in 1971. It is a controversial experiment that tried to draw conclusions about human power dynamics by assigning paid volunteers either the role of “inmate” or “guard” in a fake prison at the University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.kcrw.com/news/shows/press-play-with-madeleine-brand/sandra-bland-stanford-prison-experiment-and-opera-in-tijuana/@@images/f5196162-6ea3-4821-94d1-8ed2756ecd79.jpeg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vox.com/2018/6/13/17449118/stanford-prison-experiment-fraud-psychology-replication&#34;&gt;The Stanford Prison Experiment was massively influential. We just learned it was a fraud.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minard’s Graphic of Napoleon in Russia</title>
      <link>/2019/10/minards-graphic-of-napoleon-in-russia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/minards-graphic-of-napoleon-in-russia/</guid>
      <description>In the article “Analyzing Minard’s Visualization of Napoleon’s 1812 March,” Joanne Cheng conducts a data analysis on Minard’s graphic of Napoleon in Russia. Cheng states that Edward Tufte calls this graphic one of the “best statistical drawings ever created,” so Cheng conducted the data analysis to figure out why it is such a good graphic. The data analysis covers Napoleon and his troops’ journey into Russia and eventually Moscow in 1812, as the title indicates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minard’s Graphic of Napoleon in Russia (2)</title>
      <link>/2019/10/minards-graphic-of-napoleon-in-russia-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/minards-graphic-of-napoleon-in-russia-2/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Are you guys tired of the same boring graphs to represent data? Well, Charles Joseph Minard in 1869 certainly was. To represent Napoleon sending 400,000 troops out to attack Russia in response to Czar Alexander of Russia refusing to adhere to Napoleon’s embargo on the UK, Minard used an elegant graph depicting not only the number of troops, but also temperature and the path of the march over a map of Europe. Rather than simply showing data, Minard had a focus on story-telling which would inspire statisticians for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>