<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ethics on Stat 150 at Cal Poly</title>
    <link>/categories/ethics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ethics on Stat 150 at Cal Poly</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/ethics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Privacy in the Internet Age</title>
      <link>/2019/10/data-privacy-in-the-internet-age/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/data-privacy-in-the-internet-age/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;In 2014, the newsfeeds of 700,000 Facebook accounts were altered to explore how these alterations affected their temper. Many individuals were outraged to learn that their internet habits were being tracked and manipulated. But this is only one example of the issue of internet privacy and the ethics of it. Continue reading to learn more about how the internet has changed the way we think about privacy and ethics!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Null Results</title>
      <link>/2019/10/null-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/null-results/</guid>
      <description>In today’s scientific studies, researchers are becoming increasingly selective in what results they choose to write about and even more selective in what they publish. In his article “Why null results rarely see the light of day”, Jeffery Mervis details the prominent issue of bias toward writing and publishing strong results over null results in modern research while acknowledging the potential dangers of overemphasizing the publication of null results.In recent times, it has been overtly evident that social science experiments have been heavily in favor of writing and publication of strong results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Null Results</title>
      <link>/2019/10/null-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/null-results/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Researchers are always looking for exciting results. Whether it be a study about the link between global warming and the frequency of hurricanes, or a new drug that could be effective in curing cancer, scientists or corporations behind the studies would prefer the more exciting results. Researchers want their experiments to prove something under question or shed light on a new topic rather than showing a null result, either supporting a past study or showing no correlation between the variables. Studies with null results go unpublished nearly 80% of the time, a situation that has become known as the “file drawer” phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://behavioralscientist.org/the-study-premortem-why-publishing-null-results-is-only-the-first-step/&#34;&gt;Link to Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>